<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>tehblog</title>
    <link>http://rhg135.com/</link>
    <description>Recent content on tehblog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>No Rights Reserved &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/rhg&#34;&gt;Ricardo Gomez&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 11:00:46 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://rhg135.com/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dependency is Not Addiction</title>
      <link>http://rhg135.com/posts/dependency/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jan 2018 11:00:46 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rhg135.com/posts/dependency/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ll admit it; I am dependant on three drugs, but I am not an addict. The first of these is clear-cut, fluoxetine. I take it, good, I don&amp;rsquo;t, bad. Very bad. The second is Abilify. Same deal. The third is slightly more complex, Lyrica. When I take it I feel as I did years ago, but if I don&amp;rsquo;t then I get terrible nausea. A lot of people assume this is the same as addiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What to Pass: a Var or IFn?</title>
      <link>http://rhg135.com/posts/what-to-pass/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Aug 2015 12:33:14 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rhg135.com/posts/what-to-pass/</guid>
      <description>Mapping a function over a channel You have a function you are developing:
(defn name-string &amp;quot;Gives you the name string from a suitable map&amp;quot; [{:keys [first-name]}] first-name)  and you want to run this on maps you get over, say, a socket. Thus you shove it up a channel with an attached transducer of (map name-string) (or with a pipeline of the actual data channel, for the indirection).
A Problem Arises Now, you want to incorporate the last name as an initial.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>On Licensing</title>
      <link>http://rhg135.com/posts/on-licensing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Aug 2015 13:54:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rhg135.com/posts/on-licensing/</guid>
      <description>What about it? Copyright is broken. The whole concept of controlling copying of a resource is just not viable, and furthermore erronous. To me it is reminiscent of censorship, and we all know how well that works.
Lately I have been releasing any works to the public domain. Before discussing why, let&amp;rsquo;s examine this &amp;ldquo;copyright&amp;rdquo; thing.
What got me thinking about this I don&amp;rsquo;t recall what exactly was being looked for when I saw a project on github with an UNLICENSE file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Look Ma! I Made Post!</title>
      <link>http://rhg135.com/posts/look-ma-i-made-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2015 13:09:11 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://rhg135.com/posts/look-ma-i-made-post/</guid>
      <description>So, I have a blog. For a long time I pondered it, but never acted. Today a switch in my head finally flipped, and I became allowed to start writing; and more than that, setting up the infrastructure.
Fortunately—for me—my blog engine—cryogen—was very easy to set-up and soon I was producing. Cryogen is distributed as a template for leiningen, and this made it easy to get started. For more details see the homepage for cryogen.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>